all right so I've recently seen a video
on Tik Tok and it explained that if you
can bench press your body weight and
squat your body weight and deadlift two
times your body weight then that puts
you in the top
5% of the population in terms of
strength now that's got to be a loot of
cuz there's definitely nobody who's
actually tested that but it got me
thinking that's quite an interesting way
of framing it as in a strength challenge
that completely depends on your own body
weight so it's tailored to you and I
would quite fancy telling everyone that
I'm in the top 5% of strongest
individuals in the world however I think
that that challenge is a little bit
heavy on the old legs so like a a a
deadlift and then a squat that seems
like kind of almost similar exercises
people are going to go nuts in the
comments for me saying that also a body
weight squat is actually quite easy to
do I think I think I was able to do that
once upon a time
so I've come up with my own version of
The Challenge the mic boys strength
challenge here it is deadlift two times
your body weight bench press your body
weight and do a pullup with half of your
body weight added I weigh 70 kg so that'
be a 140 kg deadlift a 70 kg bench press
and a pullup with 35 kg attached to me
so the first thing we've got to do is
find out where I'm at with all of these
exercises let's start with bench press
oh yeah this is day one hour zero I
think the most I ever benched
was 60
kg I think I think I've done 60 it might
be 55 and that
was 14 years
ago since then I've done absolutely no
way
wait right 20 kg
easy 30 kg
piece of
cake it's definitely getting heavier now
40 every time so this is 50
kg okay that's get a little bit
harder
55 okay
55 oh that was
[Music]
Heavy okay all right I think I could do
60 this will equal my maximum bench
press 60 kg which I did when I was
19 okay a little bit nervous about this
yeah actually go go and spot
me so 1 two 3 okay and I got it
right oh my God
one two okay still
getting two reps with 60 kg well I'm as
strong as when I was 19 but I haven't
been training for bench
press so I guess I was just weak when I
was 19 but I was training all the time I
don't get it h old old man strength
that's what I've got right 65 kg here we
go one two three okay I got
it okay that's where you're at that's
where I'm
at okay so I need to add 10 kg to my
bench press all right all right next is
pull-ups now I think this is a little
bit sneaky me doing this because I'm a
climber so I feel like my pullup
strength is going to be good um and I
actually have trained with weighted
pull-ups before so I I know I can do 15
kg right rules for pullup so it doesn't
have to be from completely dead hang
like a sort of scapular pull counts and
nose has to touch the bar
you don't have to have your chin
above the bar nose touching the bar
that's the rules right we have to use
this strange
Contraption does anyone know how this
actually
works how does
this all right 5
kg easy all right this is 10
kg okay sound a bit heavy now 15
kg one okay
it's kind of things are in the
way right 20 kg okay here
goes okay go can be can barely walk with
25 right
one okay 25 is okay oh my God 30 kg you
can you can barely walk all right 30 kg
come
on no no 20 so 25's 25 is the maximum 30
is too much okay
deadlifts now this could be a problem so
I don't deadlift I don't think I've ever
deadlifted maybe did like four or five
sessions with deadlifts like it in my
life the issue with deadlifts I might
have is I don't actually really know how
to deadlift properly so I think
it's that and it's not
that all I know is you're supposed to do
that tense of tummy muscles that's I do
know
that okay I think that was
okay right 60 kg
internet is my form okay I don't feel
like it is I don't really know how to do
this okay 80
kg 140 is going to be absolutely imposs
[Applause]
yeah all right 90
right
100 I feel like this is dangerous and
stupid but still we
continue okay right
110 this is not an enjoyable lift
[Applause]
H okay 110 is where I'm at which me
leaves 30 kg more to go okay so bench
mark results uh what did we do first
we're at 60 Kg on the bench press so I
only need to put on another 10 kg and
we're at my goal pull-ups I think it's
going to be okay because I'm at 25 25 kg
um and I think I can easily put an extra
10 kg on there as just part of my
climbing training which I'm going to be
doing anyway dead lifts I think are
going to be issue I'm at what one 110
110 did you manage 110 actually managed
one were you yeah you did think I
managed 110 so that is 30 kg shy where
we need to be and to be honest that was
that was a stretch so that's going to be
the problem so I think we're in a good
position but we definitely need to focus
on
deadlifts but before I hery at a dis a
word from our sponsor thorum thorum
specializes in extremely unique rings
made from unconventional materials I
went for the Hercules ring made from
tungsten and lignum Vite the hardest
wood paired with the hardest metal the
contrast between the two materials
really make this Ring Pop thorum makes a
bunch of rings in unorthodox Styles like
this one made from a World War II gun
barrel it's nice to wear something a
little less conventional than the
standard plain band that men usually
wear these make perfect wedding rings
and they do come in ladies versions and
SE
all rings come with a lifetime warranty
which includes and this is straight off
the brief from thorum Lost stolen eaten
by a dog or whatever which is fair
enough thorum also make minimalist
pendant necklaces and watches like the
meteorite watch featuring a sleek and
clean design with a tiny slice of real
4.5 billion year old gibian meteorite
embedded in the face it's also
mechanical so no batteries ever the
husband and wife company is based in the
US and provides free shipping even
internationally and my viewers can get
20% off a truly unique piece with the
code Mike B so if you're tying the knot
or just want a truly unique ring that
contains an actual dinosaur bone check
out thorum right back to the
[Music]
video so here was my plan I'd work out
three times a week chest back and
deadlifts on separate days usually I do
four warm-up sets progressing from very
light to around 70% % of my goal and
then I'd attempt a one rep personal best
and win or lose I'd then do five sets of
four reps with the heaviest weights I
could manage I had to go slightly
lighter with chest as I couldn't lift
heavy barbell bench press without a
spotter so I used dumbbells instead and
found out my weights were around 20%
lower using dumbbells the program for
bench press and pull-ups was easy simply
lift more than you did last week and
throughout this experiment there wasn't
a workout where I wasn't stronger than
the pr pring
week except with
deadlifts all right so I bought this
thing
ofama uh weight
belt I think this will help me with
deadlifts I've never worn one and to be
honest I'm not really sure what it
actually does but everyone who deadlifts
is where knees I think you can connect
you can correct me if I'm wrong internet
I think it spreads the load a little bit
um
and sort of reduces the force on like
the discs in your back and hopefully
this helps me maintain a better posture
which makes the lift safer which means I
can lift
more not sure
[Music]
though the effects of wearing a lifting
belt were immediate with a free 10 kg
added to my Max lift and it a whole lot
[Music]
safer all right I bought these crazy
long socks because I have a tiny little
Nick here I've got a plas on it I I cut
myself when I was deadlifting like the
bar cut this part it catches on the
other leg as well excuse my gimmy jams I
don't know if I'm supposed to be nicking
my shins when I'm deadlifting I've seen
some people say that you should be doing
that but I don't know what I can do to
stop this cuz every time I deadlift I
just reopen this wound it's tiny it's
tiny but it's really painful and blood
goes everywhere so uh am I just going to
have to live with
[Music]
that by week two I'd already added 5 kg
to my bench press
that's good that's really good
progress and there were only some side
effects all right it is the night after
heavy bench press and
H it's painful my shoulders
here is it's sore it's not a good sore
either it's like a too much sore
[Music]
deadlift progress was excellent my Max
lift had increased by around 30 kg
although I think a lot of that was
because of the weight belt and I could
do 120 kg for reps now
[Music]
by week three I was almost at my final
goal for
[Music]
pull-ups and for bench
press these are the heaviest dumbbells
in this
gym so if I can left them I've ran out
of
dumbbells 60
kg okay come on let's do this
oh
easy another
wrap
right I've run out of
dumbbells however this was the first
week that my Max lift didn't increase
for
deadlifts all right that is 130
I was actually weaker than the week
previous failing at 130 kg and only
managing three reps of 120
[Music]
one I'm not sure why that happened but
the week after I was back on form with a
deadlift Personal
Best come on come on come on
nice and by the end of week four I had
achieved my goal for bench press and
weighted
[Music]
pull-ups all right so I'm going to do
something that I don't recommend anybody
does and that is to go for my maximum
bench press without a
spot two reasons for that one I've run
out of dumbbells cuz they only go to
30 um and two I don't have a spar also I
think that if I bottle it I can sort of
roll it down and sit up and get out to
be honest I'm actually really confident
I can like just done my warmup I feel
really strong I'm pretty certain this is
going to be fine right so 10 10 5 that's
25 on each side that's 50 the bar is 20
so it's 70 kg
I think I can do
two I can do
more okay that was way way too
easy right in the bag 70 kgs yeah
everything I do ruins my shins climbing
biking deadlifts pull-ups and bench in
the bag all I had to do was pull 140 kg
but I was having a bad week right this
will be the most I've ever left I think
these weigh about 17 kg each these
clips it's not even
moving give me one
minute did it come off the ground yes
nah I don't think it's going it's too
heavy it's too it's too much it's too
much this is hard as
well
ah I can't do anything that's worse than
last
time ah backwards progress
I can't do anything let's just stop well
that was that was I can't even I can't
even lift enough to like
train I hate rcking wets it's
[Music]
so after this I am never deadlifting
again
[Music]
for week six I decided I'd had enough
and just watched TV 100 kilo deadlift
I'll put it on the screen now but this
is it come on
Max come on finish it finish it yes
[Music]
come
on
come come
[Music]
on yes come on come on
wasn't even that hard it wasn't even
hard that honestly wasn't even
hard I can't I can't believe that
happened right now to complete this
challenge I have to be able to do a 70
kg bench press and a 35 kg weighted
pullup in the same session let's do that
now so that's
35 Plus the
10 20 10 5 yeah 35 is that right
yeah cool that'll
do quick warm up off the chest then bust
out 70 kg and then go to the
pub oh it does feel quite heavy
[Music]
so there we have it over a period of 46
days trading once per week per muscle
group with one week off I added 10 kg to
my bench press 10 kg to my weighted
pull-ups and 40 kg to my deadlift taking
me up to a body weight bench a 1.5 body
weight pullup and a two times body
weight dead lift as always I hope you
enjoyed this one subscribe if you
haven't already let me know what I
should try next in the comments and
thank you very much for watching
[Music]